(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-25T22:03:02.707222",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
幾千の 時を巡って今
Traveling through thousands of years, now...
僕ら出会えたの
...we have finally met.
ほら
Look,
見失わない
don't lose sight.
...ように
...so that we don't lose sight of each other,
手を離さないで
please don't let go of my hand.
星降る海
作詞・作曲：Aqu3ra
[Song: Sea of Falling Stars
Lyrics/Composition: Aqu3ra]
ねぇ 耳を澄ませて
Hey, listen closely,
星の降る音 聞こえるでしょう？
can you hear the sound of falling stars?
もっと近くに来て
Come a little closer,
誰も知らない世界が待ってるの
a world that no one knows is waiting.
手をとって踊りましょう
Let's take hands and dance.
はじまりの合図鳴らせば
If we sound the signal of the beginning,
歌おう la-la-la-！
Let's sing la-la-la!
響け la-la-la-！
Resonate la-la-la!
暗がりの道も
Even the dark paths...
月明かりが照らすの
...will be lit by moonlight.
宙、海の向こう
Across the sky and sea,
きみの元まで
all the way to where you are...
響くように歌えるかな
...I wonder if I can sing so that it reaches you.
どんな時もここで待ってるよ
No matter when, I'll be waiting here,
祈っているからさ
because I am praying for you.
ほら キラキラ輝く
Look, the stars shining so brightly
星は色褪せず太古から
have been shining since ancient times without fading.
照らし続けてる
They keep shining on us.
きみと辿り着けるさ
I know I can reach the end with you.
心には会いたい
In my heart, there's someone I want to see,
誰かがいて羅針盤みたいね
it's like a compass, isn't it?
そっと目を開けてみて
Gently try opening your eyes.
見えるものだけがリアルじゃないの
It's not just what you can see that's real.
きみといる世界は
The world I'm in with you
永遠の記憶に眠るのさ
sleeps in eternal memories.
歌おう na-na-na-！
Let's sing na-na-na!
響け na-na-na-！
Resonate na-na-na!
潮の満ち引きが
The ebb and flow of the tide...
導いてくれるの
...will guide us.
途切れたかけた夢を見ても大丈夫
Even if you dream of things breaking off, it's alright.
一人にはしないよ
I won't leave you alone.
何度だって互いの引力で
No matter how many times, by our mutual gravity,
引き寄せ合うんだよ
we are pulling each other together.
宙、海の匂い
I wonder if the scent of the sky and sea...
きみに届くかな
...will reach you.
距離なんてないのかな
I wonder if there is no such thing as distance.
どんな時もきっとどこかで
No matter when, surely somewhere...
見守っているからさ
...I am watching over you.
ほら
Look,
クシャクシャになって笑う日を
the days we laugh until we're all scrunched up,
集めて紡いでみよう
let's gather them and spin them.
未来へ踏み出す先も
Even the path we step forward into the future,
きみと心震わせて
making our hearts tremble with you.
叶うさ 今
It will come true, now...
物語を巡ろう
...let's travel through the story.
にこたんが来た！
Nico-tan is here!
ホロライブデバイス FLOWGLOW のお笑い担当、虎金にこです！
I'm Kogane Niko, the comedy representative of hololive DEV_IS FLOWGLOW!
にこたんだよー！
It's Nico-tan!
誕生日だー！
It's my birthday!
ガオー！
Rawr!
にこたん初の生誕ライブ「Seien Firestra Diva」にご来場いただき、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to Nico-tan's first birthday live, "Seien Firestra Diva"!
本日のハッシュタグは
Today's hashtag is...
#ニコたん生たん2026
...#NicoTanSeitan2026!
「たん」はにこたんの「たん」なので平仮名です
The "tan" is hiragana, from Nico-tan.
こちらでね、スクショたくさん撮って感想どしどしポストしてください！
Please take lots of screenshots and post your thoughts using it!
頼んます！
I'm counting on you!
今回のタイトル「Seien Firestra Diva」
This time's title, "Seien Firestra Diva"...
こちらは
...is a...
Firestra
炎、星、虎の３つの要素を掛け合わせた
...triple-meaning word that combines...
トリプルミーニング！にこたんが作っちゃいました！
...fire, stars, and tigers! Nico-tan made it up!
ま、にこたんが星で、みんなから炎もらってて、みたいな
You know, like Nico-tan is the star, and I get fire from everyone.
フェスでさ、初めてのフェスでみんなのペンライト赤かったでしょ？
Like at the festival—my first festival, everyone's penlights were red, right?
あれはね、炎だったの！このライブの匂わせをしていたわけです！
That was fire! I was actually hinting at this live!
計画通りってわけですよ！
Just as planned!
今回はたくさんの...
This time, a lot of...
ディーヴァと そんなにこたんの炎を感じられるような感じで
To feel Diva and Nicotan's burning passion,
たくさん歌っていく 歌唱がメインのライブになっております
we'll sing a lot in this vocal-focused concert!
1曲目は「星降る海」を歌わせていただきました
For the first song, I sang "Hoshi Furu Umi."
皆さん どうでしたでしょうか？ にこたん 清楚でしたでしょうか？
How was it, everyone? Was Nicotan pure and elegant?
この後は ゲストのディーヴァ達との時間です
Up next is our time with our guests, Diva!
それでは ゲストパート レッツゴー！
So, let's go to the guest part!
涙が夜に溶けて
My tears melt into the night,
空が今日も遠くなる
and once again the sky gets farther today.
未来が閉じたように
As if my future was closed off,
暗闇が満ちている
the darkness is filled with gloom.
あぁ 醜い心も
Ah, my hideous heart,
掠れそうな言葉も
and my words that are about to fade away,
全て見透かしたように
as if seeing right through everything,
星が輝いていた
the stars were shining.
夜鷹のように高く
If only I could fly high like a nightjar,
空を駆けていけたら
and race across the sky,
綺麗だったと囃されて
I would've been praised as beautiful,
特別になれたのに
and could have become special.
そう 俯いた目には
Yes, in my downcast eyes,
憧れしか映らない
nothing but yearning is reflected.
誰かの描いた地図じゃ
On a map drawn by someone else,
灯る場所は探せない
I can't find a place to light up.
あぁ 僕らの現状は
Ah, our current situation
意地らしくフラットして
is pathetically flat,
気を抜けば明日が
and if we let our guard down, tomorrow
昨日になってしまう
will end up becoming yesterday.
これはそう 今日を
This is, yes, the story
諦めなかった故のストーリー
of how I didn't give up on today.
風切り羽響かせて
Letting my flight feathers resonate,
空を目指して
I aim for the sky.
惨めになって嫌に
Even if I became miserable and grew to hate it,
なったって輝いてる夢を
the shining dream
叶える羽はとっくに
I will make come true; the wings
とうに生えていた
had already grown long ago.
吐き出す息が白冷めて
The breath I exhale is cooling to white,
声も聞こえなくなって
and my voice can no longer be heard,
燃え上がる体温が夜空を焦がすまで
until my flaring body heat burns up the night sky.
誰よりもっともっと向こうへって
To go further and further than anyone else,
羽ばたいた星の
the stars took flight
一瞬を
for their moment.
あぁ 夜空はずっと待っている
Ah, the night sky has always been waiting,
灯る日を待っている
waiting for the day to light up.
きっと きっと
Surely, surely.
「いつか」なんて誤魔化して
Deceiving myself with "sometime,"
「誰か」になすりつけて
and blaming it on "someone,"
「どこか」なんて慰めて
finding comfort in "somewhere,"
「何か」にすがっている
and clinging to "something."
あぁ それこそが僕だ
Ah, that is exactly who I am,
汚れきった心だ
with a heart completely stained.
夜鷹にはなれないな
I can't become a nightjar,
だから今日を飛んだんだ
that's why I flew over today.
あぁ 僕らの結末は
Ah, our ending
面白いほどナーバスで
is nerve-wracking to an interesting degree,
予測なんて一つも
since not a single prediction
当てにならないから
can be relied upon.
これはまだ僕を
This is still the story
諦めなかった故のストーリー
of how I didn't give up on myself.
枯れた喉を響かせて
Making my parched throat resonate,
後悔を追い越して
and surpassing my regrets.
世界にとって僕にとって
A role fit for the world, or fit for me,
ふさわしかった役なんて
I don't need it,
いらない 知らない 所詮
I don't care, after all...
僕は僕だった
I was just myself.
それならどうかこの涙を
In that case, please, don't forget
忘れないで
these tears of mine,
疲れ果ててこの空から
until I'm completely exhausted
落ちるまで
and fall from this sky.
今よりもっともっと向こうへって
To go further and further than now,
羽ばたいた星が
the star that took flight
泣いている
is crying.
あぁ 夜空が白みだしている
Ah, the night sky is fading to white,
日が昇りだしている そっと
the sun is rising gently.
あれから始まって
Starting from back then,
これから終わっていく
and ending from now on,
一つ、一つ、一瞬を
one by one, I'll ascertain
確かめていく
each moment.
誰とも同じじゃない
I'm not the same as anyone else,
誰にも似ていない
nor do I resemble anyone.
一人、一人、とても不確かな
One by one, we are flying
空を飛んでいるのさ
through a highly uncertain sky.
さあ 僕らの現状は
Now, our current situation
気持ち一つでシャープして
goes sharp with just a single feeling,
怯えていた明日を
we can change the tomorrow we feared
昨日に変えてしまえる
into yesterday.
これはそう 今日を
This is, yes, the story
諦めなかった故のストーリー
of how I didn't give up on today.
風切り羽響かせて
Letting my flight feathers resonate,
空を目指して
I aim for the sky.
惨めになって嫌に
Even if I became miserable and grew to hate it,
なったって輝いてる夢を
the shining dream
叶える羽はとっくに
I will make come true; the wings
とうに生えていた
had already grown long ago.
吐き出す息が白冷めて
The breath I exhale is cooling to white,
声も聞こえなくなって
and my voice can no longer be heard,
燃え上がる体温が夜空を焦がすまで
until my flaring body heat burns up the night sky.
重なって
They come together...
誰よりももっともっと向こうへ
...and soaring further away than anyone else,
羽ばたいた星の一瞬が
the star that flapped its wings shines for an instant.
青い空を照らし出している
It lights up the blue sky,
淡く光っている
glowing ever so faintly.
ずっと
Forever,
forever,
ずっと
and ever.
いつか君が瞳に灯す愛の光が
Someday, the light of love you light in your eyes...
時を超えて
...will transcend time...
滅び急ぐ世界の夢を
...and surely destroy one dream...
確かに一つ壊すだろう
...of this world rushing toward its ruin.
躊躇いを飲み干して
Swallowing your hesitation,
君が望むものは何?
what is it that you desire?
こんな欲深い憧れの行方に
At the destination of such greedy yearning,
儚い明日はあるの?
is there a fleeting tomorrow?
子供の頃 夢に見てた
Like the ancient magic...
古の魔法のように
...of which I dreamed in my childhood,
闇さえ砕く力で
with a power that can shatter even the darkness,
微笑む君に会いたい
I want to meet you, smiling.
怯えるこの手の中には
Within these trembling hands
手折られた花の勇気
lies the courage of a broken flower.
想いだけが頼る全て
My feelings are all I have to rely on
光を呼び覚ます
to awaken the light...
願い
...of my wish.
いつか君も誰かの為に
Someday, you too will desire
強い力を望むのだろう
a strong power for someone else's sake.
愛が胸を捉えた夜に
On the night love gripped your heart,
未知の言葉が生まれて来る
unknown words will be born.
迷わずに進めるなら
If I can move forward without hesitation,
心が砕けてもいいわ
I wouldn't mind even if my heart shattered.
いつも目の前の哀しみに
I want a spell to confront
立ち向かう為の呪文が欲しい
the sadness always right before my eyes.
君はまだ夢見る記憶
You are still a dreaming memory,
私は眠らない明日
while I am a sleepless tomorrow.
二人が出会う奇跡を
In order to seize the miracle
勝ち取る為に進むわ
where the two of us meet, I will press onward.
怯えるこの手の中には
Within these trembling hands
手折られた花の刃
lies the blade of a broken flower.
想いだけが生きる全て
My feelings are all I have to live on,
心に振りかざす
brandishing them within my heart...
願い
...as my wish.
囚われた太陽の輝く
Where the captured sun shines...
不思議の国の本が好きだった頃
...back when I loved the books about Wonderland,
願いはきっと叶うと
I believed in the fairy tale
教えるお伽話を
that taught me my wishes
信じた
would surely come true.
静かに咲き乱れていた
Blooming quietly in profusion...
の中...
...inside.
静かに咲き乱れていた
Quietly blooming in full glory,
古の魔法を優しく
the ancient magic gently...
世界を変える
To change the world...
力がその手にあると
...whispers that the power...
囁く
...lies in your hand.
終わらない夢を
Let's dream an endless dream...
見よう
...
君と行く
...going with you...
時の中で
...through time.
想いだけが
Only our feelings...
生きる全て
...will live as our everything.
命を
What creates life...
創るのは
...
願い
...is a wish.
ああ...
Ah...
サンドリヨン
Cendrillon
朝まで踊る
Let me dream of dancing till the dawn,
夢だけ見せて
just let me see that dream.
時計の鐘が
The chime of the clock's bell...
解く魔法
...breaks the magic.
曖昧な指
An ambiguous finger...
誘う階段
...beckons me to the stairs.
三段飛ばしに
Leaping them three at a time,
跳ねていく
I bound away.
馬車の中で
Inside the carriage,
震えてた
I was shivering.
みじめな古着
Flicking up the miserable rags...
めくりめくれ夜の舞踏
...and spinning through the night's ball.
見知らぬ顔探す
Searching for an unfamiliar face,
囁くあの声が
that whispering voice says,
握り締めた刃突き立て
Thrust the blade you hold tight...
すべてを奪えと
...and steal everything away.
孤児集う城
In the castle where orphans gather,
笑み仮面に描いて
drawing smiles onto their masks,
偽りの慈しみさえ
even a false compassion...
羽根で包む
...is wrapped in wings.
灰の中で
Within the ashes,
赤く
glowing redly,
溶けて混じる
melting and merging...
ガラスの靴
...is the glass slipper.
今更帰る
To go back now...
震えているの
...makes me shiver.
あなたが目をやる時計
At the clock you glance,
靴脱ぎ踊る
slipping off my shoe, I dance...
スロープ抜けて
...through the slope.
喉まで伸びる
Reaching up to my neck,
指の先で
at the tip of your finger...
すくうしずく
...I scoop up a drop...
口づけて
...and kiss it,
走る衝動
a running impulse
背骨抜けていく刹那
coursing down my spine in an instant.
鐘は鳴らさないで
Do not let the bells ring,
あなたにひざまずき
as I fall on my knees before you.
まだダメと叫んだ右手が
Crying "not yet," my right hand...
突き刺すサヨナラ
...thrusts a farewell.
消せない硝煙を
With indelible gun smoke,
香水にまとう姫
you are a princess wearing it like perfume.
強い瞳僕の凍った
Your strong eyes pierce right through...
仮面ごと撃ち抜く
...my frozen mask.
今も耳に
Even now, in my ears,
あなたの吐息が
your breath...
突き刺さるの
...pierces deep.
遠い夢
A distant dream...
ステンドグラスごし
Shining through the stained glass,
光る月が
the glowing moon...
君にかぶせたベール
...drapes a veil over you.
ドレス膝で裂いて
Tearing my dress at the knee,
ティアラは投げ捨てて
I cast away my tiara.
見つめ合う瞳と瞳が
Our eyes gaze into each other...
火花を放つ
...releasing sparks.
孤独な魂が
Our lonely souls...
炎を上げ惹かれ合う
...erupt in flames and are drawn to each other.
その涙 すくえないなら
If I cannot dry those tears...
まるでひとり
...it's as if I am all alone.
時よ止まれ今は
Stop, time! For now...
あなたに酔いしれて
...I am intoxicated by you.
揺れる鼓動 ひとつひとつを 刻みつけてたい
I want to carve into myself each and every beat of our swaying hearts.
とどまれ
Stay...
熱く濡れ
...hot and wet.
打ち付ける高まりに
In this surging, pounding rush...
これ以上は動けないよ
...I cannot move any more.
まるでおとぎ話の
It's just like a fairy story...
そばにいても 離れたまま
Even when we're close, we remain apart.
ひとつになれない流星 アルビレオ
Two stars that can never become one: Albireo.
ああ 君が思うよりも
Ah, even more than you think,
僕は君でいっぱいだ
I am completely filled with thoughts of you.
流星みたいな移ろいを
Even a fleeting transition like a meteor,
片時も離さず見ていたいな
I want to watch without missing a single moment.
ああ 僕が思うよりも
Ah, even more than I think,
君はずっとずっと遠い
you are so, so far away.
重なったように見える仕草
Our gestures that seem to overlap...
苦しくなるほどに美しいな
...are so beautiful they make my chest ache.
君が好きって感情が
This feeling of loving you...
残らず夜空を飾っている
...decorates the night sky without leaving a trace.
心が疼いたワケを
The reason my heart aches...
愛だなんて呼びたくない
...I don't want to call it something like love.
君は藍に浮かんだアルビレオ
You are Albireo, floating in the indigo blue sky,
この心奪ったまま
while having stolen this heart of mine.
いらないのなら返してよ
If you don't need it, give it back,
他に置き場もないけどさ
though there's nowhere else for it to go.
今もアイミスユーの切れ端が
Even now, the fragments of "I miss you"...
成層圏で燃えて
...are burning up in the stratosphere.
そばにいても離れたまま
Even when we're close, we remain apart,
ひとつになれない流星 アルビレオ
two stars that can never become one: Albireo.
何光年先で輝いてる君に
To you, who shine light-years away,
君に恋をしたんだ
I have fallen in love with you.
何光年先か測れないほど
So far away that the light-years cannot be measured,
君の光が眩しすぎたから
because your light was just too bright.
君が好きって感情で
Just with the feeling of loving you,
それだけで星が回っている
the stars keep spinning.
明日を生きる言い訳を
An excuse to live tomorrow...
愛だなんて呼んでみたい
...I want to try calling it love.
君は藍に浮かんだアルビレオ
You are Albireo, floating in the indigo blue sky,
この心奪ったまま
while having stolen this heart of mine.
いらないのなら返してよ
If you don't need it, give it back,
他に置き場もないけどさ
though there's nowhere else for it to go.
今もアイミスユーの切れ端が
Even now, the fragments of "I miss you"...
成層圏で燃えて
...are burning up in the stratosphere.
そばにいても離れたまま
Even when we're close, we remain apart,
ひとつになれない流星 アルビレオ
two stars that can never become one: Albireo.
君は藍の流星 アルビレオ
You are the indigo meteor, Albireo,
この心焦がしたまま
while leaving this heart scorched.
誰より近く 恋してた
I was in love with you, closer than anyone else,
届くわけもないのにさ
even though my feelings could never reach you.
今も温度を超えた高鳴りが
Even now, this throbbing that has surpassed temperature...
君を好きと叫ぶ
...screams that I love you.
離れていても消えないまま
Even when apart, without fading away,
子どもの頃 見上げた
When I was a child, I looked up...
夜の空に
In the night sky...
想った
I thought...
あのひとつひとつに
that each and every one of those stars...
誰かの願いがこもってる
holds someone's wish.
そのひとつが
If one of those...
あなたって
is you,
すぐ隣で
who is smiling...
笑ってて
right next to me.
ねえ時を止めれるなら
Hey, if we could stop time,
この一秒を切り取って
I would capture this single second...
星降る夜に
On this night of falling stars,
ただあなたに会いたい
I just want to see you.
あなたの名前を
Your name...
祈るようにそっと
softly, as if in prayer,
何度も
over and over...
抱きしめているよ
I am embracing it.
もう私も
I am also...
大人ね
an adult now, aren't I?
変わったこと 変わらないこと
Things that changed, things that didn't,
止まらない時計の針が 冷たく胸を刻んだ
the hands of the unstoppable clock ticked coldly in my chest.
でもあなたに出会って
But meeting you...
日々の眩しさを教えて
taught me the brilliance of everyday life.
まだ少し怖いけど
Although I am still a little scared,
今は見渡せる気がしてるよ
I feel like I can look out at the world now.
星降る夜に
On this night of falling stars,
会いたいが積もるばかり
my longing to see you only piles up.
あなたの名前を
Your name...
祈るようにそっと
softly, as if in prayer,
何度も
over and over...
抱きしめているよ
I am embracing it.
高鳴る鼓動が
My pounding heartbeat...
体を追い越していく
is outpacing my body.
私の名前を特別にしてくれたの
You made my name feel so special.
今はただ抱きしめてたいの
Right now, I just want to hold you close.
いつも想ってるよ
I am always thinking of you.
かじかんだ手に
Into these frozen hands,
温もり
warmth...
目を閉じて その先へ
Close your eyes, and go beyond...
星降る夜に
On this night of falling stars,
ただあなたに会いたい
I just want to see you.
あなたの名前を
Your name...
祈るようにそっと
softly, as if in prayer,
何度も
over and over...
抱きしめているよ
I am embracing it.
高鳴る鼓動で保存
With a pounding heartbeat,
裸足のまま駆け抜けていく
I am running through barefoot.
私の名前を特別にしてくれたの
You made my name feel so special.
あなたが照らし続けてる
You keep on shining down on me.
星降る夜に
On this night of falling stars...
Seid ihr das Essen? Nein, wir sind die Jäger!
Are you the prey? No, we are the hunters!
踏まれた花の 名前も知らずに
Without even knowing the name of the trampled flower,
地に落ちた鳥は 風を待ち詫びる
the bird that fell to the earth impatiently waits for the wind.
...る
...to come.
祈ったところで
No matter how much you pray,
何も変わらない
nothing will change.
今を変えるのは
What changes this moment
戦う覚悟だ
is the determination to fight.
屍踏み越えて
Climb over the corpses
進む意思を 嗤う豚よ
and advance, you sneering pigs!
家畜の安寧 虚偽の繁栄
Peace as livestock, false prosperity...
死せる餓狼の自由を！
Live with the freedom of starved wolves!
囚われた屈辱は
The humiliation of captivity
反撃の嚆矢だ
is the arrow of our counterattack.
城壁の其の彼方
Beyond those walls,
獲物を屠る《狩人》
the prey is slain by the Jäger!
迸る《殺意》に
His body burned by an overflowing urge to kill,
其の身を灼きながら
while his body burns,
黄昏に緋を穿つ
he will pierce the twilight with scarlet.
《紅蓮の弓矢》
The Crimson Bow and Arrow!
矢を番え追いかける
Draw the bow and chase it,
標的は逃がさない
don't let the target escape.
矢を放ち追い詰める
Fire the arrow and corner it,
決して逃がさない
never let it escape.
限界まで引き絞る
Pulled to its limit,
はち切れそうな弦
the bowstring is about to snap.
標的が息絶えるまで
Until the target drops dead,
何度でも放つ
endless volleys are fired.
獲物を殺すのは
It is not the weapon
凶器でも技術でもない
nor the skill that kills the prey,
研ぎ澄まされた
but your own finely honed
お前自身の殺意だ
intent to kill.
Wir sind der Jäger!
We are the hunters!
炎のように熱く！
Hot as flames!
Wir sind der Jäger!
We are the hunters!
氷のように冷ややかに！
Cold as ice!
Wir sind der Jäger!
We are the hunters!
おのれを矢に込めて！
Draw yourself into the arrow!
Wir sind der Jäger!
We are the hunters!
全てを貫いて行け！
Pierce all that comes before you!
Angriff auf die Titanen.
Attack on the Titans.
Der Junge von einst wird bald zum Schwert greifen.
The boy of yore will soon grab the sword.
Wer nur seine Machtlosigkeit beklagt, kann nichts verändern.
Those who only lament their powerlessness cannot change anything.
Der Junge von einst wird bald das schwarze Schwert ergreifen.
The boy of yore will soon grab the black sword.
Hass und Zorn sind eine zweischneidige Klinge.
Hatred and anger are a double-edged sword.
Bald, eines Tages, wird er dem Schicksal die Zähne zeigen.
Soon, one day, he will bare his teeth at fate.
何かを変えることが出来るのは
Those who can change things
何かを捨てることが出来るもの
are those who can discard things.
何ひとつリスク等背負わないままで
To think that without taking a single risk...
何かが叶うなど...
anything can come true...
暗愚の想定 ただの幻影 今は無謀な勇気も
Foolish assumptions, nothing more than an illusion, even what is now reckless bravery...
《自由》の尖兵 賭けの攻勢 奔る奴隷に勝利を！
The vanguard of freedom, the offensive of our gamble, victory to the running slaves!
架せられた不条理は 進撃の嚆矢だ
The absurdity thrust upon us is the arrow of our onslaught.
奪われた其の地平《世界》を望む《エレン》
The stolen horizon, the world desired by Eren.
迸る《衝動》に
As unstoppable impulse penetrates him,
其の身を侵されながら
his body is slowly taken over,
宵闇に死を運ぶ
carrying death into the twilight,
《冥府の弓矢》
the bow and arrow of hell!
ということで！
And with that!
スペシャルゲスト、可愛い可愛いちまちゃんに来ていただきました！
We have our special guest, the super cute Chima-chan, here with us!
どうもー！ にじさんじ所属、上から読んでも下から読んでも町田ちまでーす！
Hello! From Nijisanji, whether you read it from top or bottom, I'm Machita Chima!
にこちゃんお誕生日おめでとー！
Happy birthday, Nico-chan!
ありがとう！ ちまちまー！
Thank you! Chima-chima!
気づ、気づいたらこんなことになってたんだよね、ちまちま。
Before... before I knew it, things turned out like this, Chima-chima.
なんかね、大きくなっちゃった、たた。
Somehow, I've gotten so huge!
大きくなっちゃってる！
You really have gotten huge!
っていうか、すごいサイズになってるんだけど！
I mean, you've grown to an incredible size!
そうなの。後光が綺麗でしょう？
Right? Isn't my halo beautiful?
綺麗だね。似合うよ、ちまちゃん！
It is beautiful. It suits you, Chima-chan!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
いや、今日はね、ちまちゃんと「紅蓮華」を歌わせていただいたんだけど
Well, today, Chima-chan and I got to sing "Gurenge" together...
はい
Yes.
やっぱりね、ちまちゃんのハイトーンも好きなんだけど
As expected, I love Chima-chan's high tones, but...
カッコよさも好きなのよ
I also love her coolness.
おお、ありがとう
Oh, thank you.
なんか、そんな2つを交ぜられたらいいなと思って、今回選びました
I chose this song this time hoping to blend those two aspects.
ありがとう、一緒に歌えて嬉しかった！
Thank you! I was so happy we could sing together!
よかったー！ちまちゃん！
I'm glad! Chima-chan!
ニコたんとバトルできて楽しかった。もう大変だったよ、もう！
It was fun to battle with Niko-tan. It was so intense, seriously!
戦えて、戦えて良かったです
I'm glad we could fight, we could battle!
え、あのゴーレムは何だったの？
Wait, what was that golem?
うん、あれはマッチタの眷属のゴーレムです
Yeah, that was Matchita's minion golem.
そうだよね。ありがとう、言わせたみたいになってるけど
I thought so. Thanks, even though it feels like I forced you to say it.
いやもう、すごい強かったよ、マッチタのゴーレムも！
No, but Matchita's golem was really strong!
ね、めちゃくちゃ強かったけど、倒されちゃったんだよね、ニコちゃんに
Right, it was super strong, but Niko-chan defeated it.
ニコちゃん強かったからね
Because Niko-chan is strong.
ニコちゃんのおかげで、なんか、マッチタ自身もパワーが、なんか、どんどん削がれて...
Thanks to Niko-chan, Matchita's own power is somehow getting drained...
ちまちゃん！
Chima-chan!
あぁ、もうダメかもしれない！
Ah, this might be it!
なんだか、体が...
Somehow, my body...
時間がない！
There's no time!
ちまちゃん本当に本当におめでとう！ありがとう！これからもよろしくね！またね！バイバイ！
Chima-chan, happy birthday, thank you so much! I look forward to working with you! See you, bye-bye!
バイバーイ！ちまちゃん！
Bye-bye, Chima-chan!
Party is over
それでも踊りたかった
Yet I still wanted to dance
眠れないくらい
To the point of being unable to sleep
情熱の火はいつしか
The fire of passion will someday...
いつの日にか
...on some day...
はなから気付いている
I've realized from the start
焔はいつか消える
That the flame will someday burn out
ねぇ なにもいらないはずだった
Hey, I wasn't supposed to need anything
なのにまだ I'm so silly
And yet, I'm still so silly
ああ まだ間に合う
Ah, there is still time
ああ あとはない
Ah, there is no turning back
Baby
Sorry darling そんなに甘くないよ
Sorry darling, it's not that sweet
demo kitto sonna ni waruku nai yo / でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
But surely, it's not that bad either
Give me fire
Light it up baby 燃やしちゃうぜ yeah
Light it up baby, I'll burn it all down, yeah
Yeah...
Ah...
燃えろよ燃えろよ この世も燃えろ
Burn, oh burn, let this world burn too
夜千代も八千代変わりもせずに 人の生り、通り、過ち 全部燃やせや、お八百八
Eternally and endlessly, without change / The way humans are, their paths, their mistakes—burn them all down, like Oshichi
入れ代わる火の粉が 傷付けるのが仕事
The shifting sparks, their job is to cause pain
ガソリン、灯油、オイル 燃える様をお見事
Gasoline, kerosene, oil—what a spectacular sight as they burn
火遊びはしない 戻りもねえ、逃げ場もない
This is no playing with fire, no going back, no escape
散らかったカルマ トラウマ 燃やし尽くすマグマ、ドラマ
Scattered karma, trauma, magma burning it all down, the drama
このあくなき渇き 青い炎が見たい
This unquenchable thirst, I want to see the blue flame
いつしか火と人の一つとなり やがて全て一つとなり
Unnoticed, fire and humans become one, and eventually everything becomes one
Party is dying
でもまだ消えてないから
But because it hasn't gone out yet
忘れてみたい
I want to try forgetting
情熱の火はいつしか
The fire of passion will someday...
いつの日にか
...on some day...
身体は傷ついている
Our bodies are scarred
僕らはいつか消える
We will someday disappear
緩やかに若さを溶かして だから言え I'm so silly
Gently melting away our youth, so say it, I'm so silly
ああ まだ間に合う
Ah, there is still time
ああ あとはない
Ah, there is no turning back
Baby
Sorry darling そんなに甘くないよ
Sorry darling, it's not that sweet
でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
But surely, it's not that bad either
Give me fire
Light it up baby 燃やしちゃうぜ yeah
Light it up baby, I'll burn it all down, yeah
Yeah...
足りない 足りない 足りない 注ぐ火に油
Not enough, not enough, not enough, pour oil on the fire
Sorry darling, hurry up! ああ、まだ間に合う
Sorry darling, hurry up! Ah, there is still time
Sorry darling, hurry up! ああ、あとはない
Sorry darling, hurry up! Ah, there is no turning back
Give me fire
Light it up baby 燃やしちゃうぜ yeah
Light it up baby, I'll burn it all down, yeah
Party is over
それでも踊りたかった
Yet I still wanted to dance
魂の色は何色ですか
What color is your soul?
もういっそ折れたままで
I'd rather stay broken...
捨てるほど逃げ出すほど強くないよ ほら
...because I'm not strong enough to throw it away or run away.
もう一度鼓動高鳴る何か確かめたいなんて
To want to check what makes my heart beat fast once more...
わからないけど
...I don't really know why.
形のないものばかりが
Only things without a shape...
大切になっていく
...keep becoming important.
飾らない言葉だけが
Only unadorned words...
強く結ばれてる
...are strongly tied together.
また躓いて転がって それでも砕けない
Tripping and rolling over again, but still not breaking.
魂の色は何色ですか
What color is your soul?
ただ傷ついて強がって それでも見つけたいよ
Just getting hurt and acting tough, but I still want to find it.
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
I am confirming the shape of my soul.
深い霧の底でひとり
Alone at the bottom of the deep fog,
扉と鍵を探す
searching for the door and the key.
おとぎ話はほら
You see, fairy tales...
泡のように全部消えて
...disappear completely like bubbles,
残ったのは残像だけ
leaving only afterimages.
次のページへ
On to the next page.
伸びていく枝葉が別れて
The growing branches split apart,
それぞれの道を行く
each taking their own path.
寂しい思い出だけが
Only lonely memories...
強く根を張っている
...are spreading their roots deeply.
また貫いて失って それでも挫けない
Piercing through and losing again, but still not discouraged.
心はどこに 器はどこに
Where is the heart? Where is the vessel?
ただ残されて抜け落ちて それでも伝えたいよ
Just left behind and falling away, but I still want to convey it.
魂の響きを 魂の意思を
The resonance of the soul, the will of the soul.
ずっと
Forever.
魂の色は
The color of the soul...
何色ですか
...what color is it?
赤色ですか
Is it red?
青色ですか
Is it blue?
魂の色は
The color of the soul...
何色ですか
...what color is it?
透明な過去に 不透明な未来に
In a transparent past, in an opaque future,
生きるあなたは何色ですか
what color are you, who lives in them?
また躓いて転がって それでも砕けない
Tripping and rolling over again, but still not breaking.
魂の色は何色ですか
What color is your soul?
ただ傷ついて強がって それでも見つけたいよ
Just getting hurt and acting tough, but I still want to find it.
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
I am confirming the shape of my soul.
ずっと
Forever.
その胸にしまった日にあこがれた
I yearned for the day tucked away inside that chest,
飲み込まれて消されてしまいそうで
feeling like I'd be swallowed up and erased.
夕焼けみたいに温かくて
It was warm like a sunset,
寂しくて強かったその日に
lonely and strong, on that day.
言葉選ん...
Choosing my words...
手あげて間違えた
I raised my hand by mistake.
よく晴れた日を未だに思い出す
I still remember that beautifully clear day.
目を伏せたらもう動けなくて
Once I cast my eyes down, I couldn't move.
嫌われていないこと祈るばかり
All I do is pray that I'm not hated.
心全部見せてくれた
You showed me your whole heart,
何一つできなかったのに
even though I couldn't do a single thing for you.
どんな今を生きていますか
What kind of present are you living now?
好きだった歌はまだ聞こえますか
Can you still hear the song you used to love?
くしゃみ一つで笑った泣き顔保存
A tearful face that laughed at a single sneeze.
離れてもそばにいる聞こえるよ
Even if we're apart, I'm by your side. I can hear you,
生きているよ
I am alive.
口先だけで繋いだ知らない手
An unfamiliar hand held with mere lip service,
それでも離さない一人は怖い
yet I still won't let go, because being alone is scary.
伝えたい一言がいろんなことが
The word I want to say, and so many things...
奇跡みたいに思えてどうしようもない
They feel like miracles, and I can't help it.
少しずつ感じなくなっていく
Gradually, I'm starting to lose my senses.
悔しかった帰り道忘れていく
I'm forgetting the way back where I felt so frustrated.
そうしなきゃダメな時が来る
A time comes when I have to do just that,
それでも納得できないこともある
but even so, there are things I cannot accept.
黙ったままの指切り
A silent pinky promise.
何が変わるかわからないわからないまま
Without knowing, without knowing what will change.
星を呼んで道を知るように
Just like calling to the stars to find the way,
君の声で僕は進めるんだ保存
your voice is what keeps me moving forward.
さよならを言った場所から
From the place where we said goodbye,
離れても聞こえるよ約束がある
even if we are apart, I can hear it—there is a promise.
その胸に閉まった日に憧れた
I yearned for the day tucked away inside that chest.
こんな重い荷物抱えたりしたでしょう
You must have carried such heavy burdens, didn't you?
その日がその目に見えなくても
Even if that day is invisible to those eyes,
このまぶたの裏に柔らかく残る
it softly remains behind these eyelids.
さよならを言った場所には
At the place where we said goodbye,
君の声がずっと輝くんだ
your voice will forever shine.
君が君を見失っても
Even if you lose sight of yourself,
僕が見つけ出せるよ君の声で
I will find you, guided by your voice.
どんな今を生きていますか
What kind of present are you living now?
僕の歌が今聞こえますか
Can you hear my song right now?
くしゃみ一つで取り戻せるよ
With just a single sneeze, we can bring it back.
離れてもそばにいる聞こえるよ保存
Even if we're apart, I'm by your side. I can hear you,
生きているよ
I am alive.
ということでサザンクロスを歌わせていただきました！
And with that, we performed Southern Cross!
ちびにこちゃん、一緒に歌ってくれてありがとう！
Chibi-Niko-chan, thank you so much for singing with me!
こっちおいでー！
Come over here!
わー！ありがとう！
Wow! Thank you!
にこちゃんだ！
It's Niko-chan!
にこちゃんだよ！ちびにこちゃん、ようやく会えたね！
It is Niko-chan! Chibi-Niko-chan, we finally met!
っていうか本当にちっちゃいね！可愛い！
But seriously, you are so tiny! So cute!
えへへ、ありがとう！
Ehehe, thank you!
可愛い、可愛い！もう目の中に入れても痛くないよね、自分だからね。もう目の中に入れたいよね！
So cute, so cute! You're so cute I could put you in my eye and it wouldn't hurt, since you're me. I really want to put you in my eye!
ちょっと、にこちゃん！食べちゃいたい！
Hey, Niko-chan! I want to eat you up!
えっ、ちょっと何やってるの？
Wait, what are you doing?
よしよし、可愛い、可愛い、可愛い！
There, there, so cute, so cute, so cute!
ち、ちびにこちゃん可愛い！
Ch-Chibi-Niko-chan is so cute!
くすぐったい！にこちゃん怖いんだけど！
That tickles! Niko-chan, you're being creepy!
ごめんごめん！
Sorry, sorry!
にこちゃん、この後大切なお知らせたくさんしなきゃいけないから、ちょっと待っててくれるかな？
Niko-chan has a lot of important announcements to make after this, so could you wait a bit?
この後の面談でじっくりお話し...
We can talk properly in our meeting later...
あっ、うん、わかった！
Oh, yeah, okay!
とりあえず、にこちゃん、この後も頑張ってね！
Anyway, Niko-chan, keep doing your best after this too!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
リスナーさんもバイバーイ！
Listeners, bye-bye too!
はーい！バイバイ、ちびにこちゃん！可愛い！
Alright! Bye-bye, Chibi-Niko-chan! So cute!
はー、ということで、ちびにこちゃんに来ていただきました！
Phew, and with that, we had Chibi-Niko-chan join us!
可愛かったねー！
That was so cute!
配信はまだまだ続くのですが、
The stream is still going to continue, but...
ここで告知行っちゃおっか！いくつかございます。
let's make some announcements here! We have a few.
まずは、こちら！
First up, here they are!
小金井ニコ誕生日記念2026のグッズが出ます！やったー！
Kogane Niko Birthday Celebration 2026 merchandise is coming out! Yay!
早速ね、1つずつグッズを紹介させてください。
Let me introduce each item one by one right away.
1つ目は、こちら！
First up, this one!
「清楚ニコたん アクリルジオラマスタンド」イラストは本田ロアロ先生に描いていただきました！
"Pure Niko-tan Acrylic Diorama Stand." The illustration was drawn by Honda Roaro-sensei!
今回の生誕のテーマを元に、ディーヴァ清楚なニコたんをイメージして描いていただいてます。
Based on the theme of this birthday, it's drawn with the image of Diva Pure Niko-tan.
清楚なニコたんをね、ぜひアクリルジオラマスタンドとしておうちにお迎えしてください。
Please welcome the pure Niko-tan to your home as an acrylic diorama stand.
お次は、こちら！
Next up, this one!
「ちびニコたん ランダム缶バッジ」
"Chibi Niko-tan Random Tin Badge."
今回もグッズ化してしまいました！
We made them into merchandise again!
いろんな表情やポーズのちびニコたんが、全部で4種類。ランダムで1種類だけ入ってます。
There are 4 types in total featuring Chibi Niko-tan in various expressions and poses. One is included at random.
どのちびニコたんが出てくるかは、開けてからのお楽しみ！
Which Chibi Niko-tan you get will be a surprise until you open it!
続いては、こちら！
Moving on, this one!
「ちびニコたんを0距離で？！ぬいぐるみショルダーバッグ」
"Chibi Niko-tan at Zero Distance?! Plushie Shoulder Bag."
いつでもどこでも、ちびニコたんと一緒にお出かけできます。
You can go out with Chibi Niko-tan anytime, anywhere.
いろんなところに連れて行ってあげてください。あの、頭を上げてね、小物入れられます。
Please take her with you to various places. Um, you can lift her head to put small items inside.
最後は、こちら！
And finally, this one!
「獲物を見つけたニコたん ぬいぐるみキーホルダー」
"Niko-tan Who Found Her Prey Plushie Keyring."
単体で持って行くもよし、さっきのショルダーバッグにつけて行くのもよし。
You can carry it on its own, or attach it to the shoulder bag from earlier.
いろんなところにつけて、ニコたん推しをアピールできます！
You can attach it to various places to show off your love for Niko-tan!
改めて、フルセットはこちら！
Once again, here is the full set!
可愛いし、美しい！ちびニコたんを今回もね、がっつりできて、
It's cute and beautiful! We were able to feature Chibi Niko-tan heavily again,
清楚なニコたんもがっつりできて、本当に嬉しいです。
and also pure Niko-tan. I'm so happy.
使いやすいものも多いのでね、ぜひゲットしてください。さらに！フルセット購入特典もございます。こちら！
There are many practical items, so please make sure to get them. Furthermore!
フルセット購入特典「直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入り チケット風カード」
Full set purchase bonus: "Autographed & Foil-stamped Duplicate Message Ticket-style Card"
ライブのチケットみたいになってます、今回のこれ。と、
This time, it looks like a live concert ticket. And,
特典のASMRボイスが出ます。
bonus ASMR voice is included.
タイトルは、「野性に戻ってしまった成人女性(虎)」です。
The title is "An Adult Female Who Returned to the Wild (Tiger)".
トラ？！
Tiger?!
トラ！最後に「(虎)」ってことはまあ、トラなんだよな。そういうことだよな、グッズさんよ。
Tiger! Since it says "(Tiger)" at the end, it must mean a tiger. That's how it is, Mr. Merch Creator!
チケット風カードにはね、あの、心を込めて、すべて手書きでサインをさせていただきます。
On the ticket-style cards, I will put my heart into signing every single one of them by hand.
ボイスは、トラとして野性に戻ってしまったニコたんを取り戻しに行くリスナー、というテーマで収録です。
As for the voice, it was recorded under the theme of "the listener going to rescue Niko-tan, who has returned to the wild as a tiger."
どういうことなんだろう、本当に。まあでも、ちょっと気になりますよね？ぜひ聴いてみてください。ちなみに過去一恥ずかしそうな内容です。
What does that even mean, really? But it sounds intriguing, right? Please give it a listen. By the way, it's the most embarrassing content I've ever recorded.
グッズは、配信後カートオープンです。フルセットは、数量限定ではございません。なので、ゆっくり購入してください。
The merch cart opens after the stream. The full set is not limited in quantity, so please take your time with your purchase.
大事な告知は、まだあります。が、
There are still more important announcements, but...
その前に、1曲、歌わせていただこうかなと思います。ちょっとマイクも変えますね。
before that, I'd like to sing a song. I'll change my mic first.
次の曲は、ニコたんのことを知って応援してくれている皆さんにとっても、とても思い出深いあの曲となっております。歌ってみたも出させていただいている曲なんですけど、
The next song is a very memorable one for everyone who knows and supports Niko-tan. It's a song for which I've also released a cover version,
みんな、覚えてるかな？それでは聴いてください。「ヒカリヘ」。
I wonder if everyone remembers? Well then, please listen. "Hikari e".
理想現実ワンクリック　ヒカリの速度に変わっても
With a single click of ideals and reality, even if it changes to the speed of light,
地球のまえより遠い距離　アダムとイヴにはなれない
a distance further than the front of the Earth, we can't be Adam and Eve.
かなしみの生まれた場所たどって
If I could trace the place where sadness was born,
その傷優しく触れて癒せたら
and gently touch and heal those wounds...
溢れるおもい　愛は君を照らすヒカリになれる
My overflowing feelings... Love can become the light that illuminates you.
切ないほどに
So painful...
たとえば未来そこにあたしがいないとしても
Even if, for example, I am not there in the future,
今はそっと抱きしめてあげる
I will gently hold you tight for now.
運命だって引き寄せて輝き続けたいよ
I want to pull even fate close and keep on shining.
奇跡だって起こせるって信じたい　信じたい
I want to believe, I want to believe that we can even make miracles happen.
信じた
I believed...
遠慮 配慮 言葉のサイド 感情記号化されても
Even if reservations, consideration, and words are turned into emotion symbols...
心の奥まで伝わらない
...they don't reach the depths of my heart.
本当の声を聴かせて
Let me hear your true voice.
すべてのことに終わりがあるなら
If there is an end to everything...
苦しみさえいつか消えるはずだから
...even suffering is bound to fade away someday.
溢れる想い
My overflowing feelings...
愛は胸を焦がす痛みに変わる
...love turns into a pain that burns my chest,
愛おしいほどに
...so precious.
たとえば世界中の声に責められても
Even if I'm condemned by the voices of the world,
私が全部受け止めてあげる
I will accept all of it for you.
人は悲しみを知るために生まれたの？
Are people born to know sadness?
そんなことない もっと愛を知りたい
That's not true, I want to know more love.
この暗闇を超えるためにあるのなら
If we are born to overcome this darkness...
幸せはいつだってそこにあるのに
...happiness is always right there.
溢れる想い
My overflowing feelings...
愛は君を照らす光になれ
...may love become a light to illuminate you,
切ないほどに
...so painfully.
たとえ未来そこに私がいないとしても
Even if I'm not there in the future,
今はそっと抱きしめてあげる
I will gently embrace you now.
運命だって引き寄せて輝き続けたいよ
I want to pull even fate close and keep on shining.
奇跡だって起こせるって信じた
I believed that I could even make miracles happen.
信じた
I believed...
ということで、なんと！miwaさんに来ていただきました！
And with that, believe it or not, miwa-san has come to join us!
miwaさん！
miwa-san!
はーい。タッチ！
Hi! Touch!
えへへへ
Ehehehe
miwaさんだ！こう、こうじゃ！
It's miwa-san! Like this, like this!
触れ合っている。
We're touching!
すごい！miwaさんに来ていただきました！
Amazing! miwa-san is here with us!
miwaです。
I'm miwa.
miwaさん！あの、あの、ニコさん！
miwa-san! Um, Niko-san!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！めっちゃ嬉しいです！
Thank you so much! I'm so happy!
実は、miwaさんとはデビュー当初あの「歌ってみた」ヒカリヘを創らせていただきまして
Actually, miwa-san and I made the "Hikari e" cover around my debut...
その時からのご縁で、まさかこうして一緒に歌えることが可能なんて、本当に夢のようでございます、miwaさん！
...and thanks to that connection, I can't believe we're singing together. It's truly like a dream, miwa-san!
こちらこそです。とっても嬉しいです。
The pleasure is mine! I'm so glad to be here.
美しかった…！そして、ここでなんと重大な告知、二つ目がございます！
It was beautiful...! And now, we have our second major announcement!
なんと、miwaさんに作詞作曲をしていただいた、ニコたん初めてのオリ曲がございます！
Believe it or not, we have Niko-tan's very first original song, written and composed by miwa-san!
イェーイ！やったー！
Yay! Hurrah!
miwaさん、そのタイトルをぜひ発表していただいてもいいでしょうか？
miwa-san, would you please do us the honor of announcing the title?
私でいいんでしょうか？ 当たり前じゃないですか！
Is it really okay for me to do it? Of course it is!
それでは発表させていただきます。
Well then, let me make the announcement.
タイトルは「星炎」です！
The title is "Seien" [Star Flame]!
「星炎」です！星の炎と書いて「星炎」です！
"Seien"! Written with the characters for "star" and "flame"!
実は今回のライブのタイトルにもなってます。「星炎 -FIRESTALIVA-」
It's actually the title of this live concert too: "Seien -FIRESTALIVA-".
今回のセットリストも星と炎の曲で作られていて
The setlist today was also crafted around the themes of stars and flames...
今回最後にこれからmiwaさんに作っていただいた「星炎」を歌わせていただきます！
...and for our final song, I will perform "Seien", written for me by miwa-san!
ニコたんがこうしてホロライブに来て、こうやってmiwaさんと出会ったり、嬉しいこともたくさんありながらも、やっぱり
Since coming to Hololive, meeting miwa-san like this, and having many happy moments, I've still...
活動で悩んだことだったり、辛いこととか、なんか葛藤...
...faced worries with my activities, hard times, and inner conflicts...
...音とか、そういうものが色々あったんですけど
...various sounds and things like that,
それを全部miwaさんに聞いてもらって、歌詞を作っていただきました。曲も作っていただきました。
but I had miwa listen to all of them, and she wrote the lyrics and composed the song for me.
本当に皆さん、ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much, everyone!
ありがとうございました。もう、本当に光栄です。
Thank you so much. It's truly an honor.
ね、nicoさんの曲を一緒に書けて、本当に光栄ですし
I'm so honored to have written a song together with Nico,
今日一緒に『光』を歌えて、本当に嬉しかったです。
and I was so happy to sing "Hikari" together today.
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
では、この後歌う新曲『星炎』、楽しみにしてるね。私も！
So, I'm really looking forward to your new song, "Seien," which you'll sing next. Me too!
みんなと一緒にそこで見てるよ！
I'll be watching it right there with everyone!
ここにいるの？！あはは
You're going to stay here?! Ahaha
皆さん、これからもよろしくお願いします！
Everyone, please continue to support us!
よろしくお願いします。
Please do.
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you!
バイバイー！がんばって！はい！
Bye-bye! Good luck! Yes!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
もうmiwaさん、可愛いし、美しいし、歌声は素晴らしいし、もう素敵だし、本当に本物のmiwaさんだ！
Miwa-san is so cute, beautiful, has an amazing voice, and is just so wonderful... She's truly the real miwa!
ということで、新曲を歌うために、ステージに移動したいと思います。
So, in order to sing the new song, I will move to the main stage.
聴いてください。『星炎』
Please listen to "Seien."
星炎
[Title: Seien (Star Flame)]
自信なんてなかった ひとりだってよかった
I had no confidence; I thought being alone was fine
プライドに隠れて
Hiding behind my pride
誰かの視線 気になってばかりで
Always worrying about how others saw me
閉じこもってた保存
I kept myself shut away
綺麗だなんて 思えなくて
I couldn't think of myself as beautiful
笑えなかったんだ
And I couldn't even smile
涙で滲んだ 画面の向こう
Beyond the screen blurred by my tears,
ふいに溶けた心
my heart suddenly melted
触れてくれた声
The voice that reached out to touch me
「君のおかげで笑えたよ」
"Thanks to you, I was able to smile"
その言葉がずっと保存
Those words have always
この胸を灯す
lighted up my heart
ただ一つの光
As my one and only light
Fire, take me higher
消えそうな声を歌に変えて
Turning my fading voice into a song
弱さ 抱きしめながら
While embracing my weakness
届けと叫ぶように燃やす炎
A flame burning as if crying out to reach you
炎
Flame
Fire, take me higher
君の明日を照らしたい
I want to illuminate your tomorrow
救われたくて 100以上出しきって
Wanting to be saved, giving more than 100%
疲れ果てた夜
On those exhausted nights
これからもずっと歩き続けたい
I want to keep on walking forward from now on.
Fire, take me higher
消えそうな声を歌に変えて
Turning my fading voice into a song,
弱さ抱きしめながら
while embracing my weakness,
届けと叫ぶように燃やす
I'll burn as if screaming for it to reach you,
炎
a flame,
a flame...
Fire, take me higher
君の明日を照らしたい
I want to light up your tomorrow.
にゃこの歌を聴いてくれてありがとう
Thank you for listening to Nyako's song!